Professor Luo
罗老师
What kind of work will you arrange for me?
您会给我安排什么样的工作
You are contradictory.
您很矛盾
Mr. Tyler.
泰勒先生
Macroelectrons need artificial lightning for excitation.
宏电子需要人造闪电激发
Only then will it have all the attributes of a quantum state weapon.
才会具备量子态武器的全部属性
Dr. Ding
丁博士
I still hope
我还是希望
you can lead my experiment.
你能做我的实验主导人
No need to
不用
This experiment will fail.
这实验肯定失败
The B436 project experiment has gone too far.
B436项目实验已经走得太远了
I advise you
我劝你
enough is enough.
适可而止
Von Neumann
冯・诺伊曼
Frederick Tyler's Wall Breaker
弗里德里克・泰勒的破壁人
Brother Luo
罗老弟
Are you resting?
休息好了吗
Time to go.
该出发了
Not yet.
还没呢
Wait a while.
再等一会儿
Slow down slow down.
慢一点儿慢一点儿
Close call close call.
收油收油
Traffic lights ahead.
前面红绿灯
What?
什么
Luo Ji.
罗辑
There's a car ahead, slow down.
前面有车慢一点儿
Brake now.
现在刹吗
Change lanes.
变道变道
This kid..
这小子
Slightly to the right.
稍微往右一点儿
Do you want more?
要不要多一点儿
Change lanes.
变道变道
Turn on the right turn signal.
打右转向灯
The optimal route has been re-planned.
已重新规划最优路线
Please continue on the road to the right.
请沿右侧道路继续前行
There's a car ahead, slow down.
前面有车慢一点儿
Hit the brakes.
点一下刹车
Should we get gas?
现在收油吗
Turn left turn left.
往左往左
A little slower.
稍微慢一点儿
The current road condition is good.
当前路况较好
It is recommended to turn on the Changan Zhuge intelligent driving assistance setting.
推荐开启长安诸葛智能驾驶辅助功能
In order to ensure the supplementary tasks of various scientific research materials for high-altitude stations
为保障高空站各类科研物资补充任务
the ground operation center will optimize the logistics data model in the near future.
地面运行中心将于近期优化物流数据模型
I said, what do they eat?
我说你们是干什么吃的
The two living people can't stand it
俩大活人都看不住
I just need to go to the bathroom.
我就上个厕所的工夫
Turn around and run away.
回头人就跑了
Eyes act as light bulbs
眼睛当灯泡使啊
If I don't ask people, I will go to Trisolaran
我要不问人不跑三体星去了
Haven't found them yet?
还没查到吗
Them.
人呢
Him and Zhuang Yan.
他和庄颜
Nothing can happen to them.
谁都不能出事儿
Found them.
查到了
I sent you their location.
发您定位仪了
I'm sorry Mr. Shi.
对不起史队
It's..
我们
It's all gone wrong.
都已经上去一大截了
You're dead when I come back.
等我回来你们死定了
Hurry up and find the person in charge here.
赶紧去找这儿负责人
I'm going in now.
我现在就要进舱
Inspection failed
检阅未通过
The wallfacer is top priority.
面壁者在上面
I know.
我知道
Be sure not to let civilians mix in.
一定不让闲杂人等混进来
Where is the person in charge of this cabin?
这舱负责人呢
Bring him here right away.
让他马上过来
I am.
我就是
Who are you?
你谁啊
That line.
那行
I am that.
我是那
Ministry of Earth Defense and Security.
地球防务安全部的
Hurry up.
赶紧发车
I don't care what department you are.
我不管你是什么部
Badge.
工牌呢
Didn't you answer all my calls?
电话你不都接了吗
Didn't I make it clear?
没说清吗
These unlucky bastards
这帮倒霉玩意儿
people can't stand it.
人看不住
I can't even say a thing.
连个话也说不清
Sorry.
对不起
No badge no entry.
没工牌没位置
What's do you mean?
什么意思
Here.
这儿
Signed and sealed.
签名盖章
I talked to you over the phone.
电话里都讲了
I am Shi Qiang.
我就是史强
Stop me.
拦着我
Who is responsible for the safety of Wallfacer Luo Ji?
面壁者罗辑的安全谁来负责
You?
你吗
Can you manage it?
你担得起吗你
Sorry sorry.
抱歉抱歉
Mr. Shi.
史队
I'm really sorry.
实在是对不起啊
Go, quickly.
快走快走
As soon as I got the call from PDC
我一收到PDC电话
I came here right away.
立马就赶过来了
Stop talking nonsense and hurry up.
甭废话了赶紧的
Ok ok ok.
日曰日 aEaEaE
Ready to go.
准备发车是
Where is my seat?
我位置呢
Mr. Shi please this way.
请史队移步
We have prepared temporary VIP seat for you.
我们为您准备了临时贵宾专座
The N49 carrier pod is about to launch.
N49运载舱即将启动
The cabin has been sealed and pressurized
哥们儿 全舱已完成密封增压
Excuse me.
借过
Please confirm the safety protection device in the cabin.
请舱内人员确认安全防护装置
Strictly abide by space transportation safety regulations.
严格遵守太空运输安全条例
What kind of VIP..
什么鬼VIP （贵宾）
The carrier cabin has entered the second stage of acceleration.
运载舱进入第二阶段加速
Maximum acceleration.
当前加速过载
Please adjust your sitting posture.
请调整坐姿
Rake a deep breath.
保持深呼吸
I am really happy.
我好开心
What?
什么
because
因为
it's
难得
only
只有
us.
我们
Launch procedure starting.
发射程序启动
The electromagnetic thruster is warmed up.
电磁推进器预热完毕
The self-test of the full launch system is normal.
全发射系统自检无异常
Track free of obstacles.
轨道无障碍物
The pod is activated.
舱体已启动
About to accelerate to orbit.
即将进入加速轨道
Superconducting electromagnetic flux stabilization.
超导电磁体磁通跳跃稳定
Magnettic winding conductor mechanically fastened succuessfully.
磁体绕组导体机械固定正常
Dynamic acceleration is normal.
动力加速正常
Suspension shelf is closed.
悬浮架已闭合
Side impulse balance and stability.
侧向冲量平衡稳定
The line has been adjusted in both directions.
线路已进行双向调节
Preparing for a Weapon Effectiveness Evaluation of Ball Lightning.
准备球状闪电的武器效能评估
Pay attention to its numerical fluctuations in the space environment.
留意它在太空环境的数值波动
Acknowledged.
收到
Ghost 1 automatic remote program setup is complete.
幽灵1号自动远程程序设置完毕
Inspectors in the acceleration zone and capture ship have been evacuated.
加速区和捕捉船内的检查人员已撤离
Confirm that all experimenters are in the safe zone.
确认所有实验人员处于安全区域内
Confirmed.
确认完毕
Automated program is running.
自动程序正在运行
Start the remote release and reclamation process.
开始远程释放和回收流程
The ball lightning data is started.
球闪数据调出来
I want to verify parameters.
我要核实参数
Received
收到
Initiator has been corrected.
激发程序已修正
Ball lightning energy level reduced to safe values.
球闪能级跌至安全值
Docking completed.
对接完成
A stable capture electromagnetic field has been formed.
已形成稳定捕获电磁场
Ball lightning excitation completed.
球闪激发完成
Confirm track position again.
再次确认轨道位置
Confirmed.
确认无误
Ghost 1 is on the preset track.
幽灵1号正沿预设轨道
Go to target attack position.
前往靶区攻击位置
What happened?
怎么回事
I changed it.
是我改的
We just want to observe the energy redundancy after the ball lightning attack.
我们只是要观察球闪攻击后的能量冗余
It's absolutely safe.
完全可以
Do you really think it's an experiment?
你还真以为是在做实验
This is preparation for war.
这是在备战
Dr. Elena
埃琳娜博士
Even children have to face the three-body crisis.
连小孩子都得面对三体危机
Why do you talk about safety?
你凭什么谈安全
But the alternate abort procedure..
但备用中止程序
Who's in charge here?
这儿到底谁说了算
You.
您
Mr. Tyler.
泰勒先生
If it weren't for the fact that I'm a Wallfacer
要不是因为我是面壁者
You wouldn't have the chance to be here.
你有资格站在这儿
All departments.
所有部门
Restore original values.
恢复原始数值
The trigger has been rolled back.
激发程序已回档
The ball lightning increased to the current highest energy level.
球闪跃迁至当前最高能级
Hey, brother.
兄弟
How long do we have until the top ring?
咱还有多久到上头那环
Please note
请注意
The carrier cabin is about to arrive at the high-altitude transfer station.
运载舱即将抵达高空中转站
For your safety
为了您的安全
before the carrier cabin comes to a complete stop
在运载舱完全停稳前
do not disengage the safety device.
请勿解开安全装置
Come see.
快来看
There.
那儿
Come.
来
Hello passengers
各位乘客你们好
Space Elevator 1 consists of three main sections.
1号太空电梯由三个主体构成
Ground base.
地面基座
Low-altitude transfer station and high-altitude transfer station.
低空中转站与高空中转站
In
其中
the high-altitude transfer station is the core section of the space elevator.
高空中转站作为太空电梯的核心主体
It undertakes scientific research applications,
承担着科研应用
deep space exploration
深空探索
and various tasks such as device testing.
装置试验等多种工作
It is a multi-purpose comprehensive mission platform integrating cutting-edge human technology.
是集人类前沿科技于一体的多用途综合任务平台
At present
目前
The high-altitude transfer station is also responsible for supporting the construction of the space dock.
高空中转站还同时负责支援太空船坞的建设工作
There.
那儿
Which has now entered the second phase of the plan.
现已进入桁架二期阶段
Four centuries from now
四个世纪后
the space fleet will launch from here.
太空舰队将从这里出发
I'm thinking
我在想
about?
怎么
Everything.
我们
Are we really in an era of crisis?
真的在危机纪元吗
All team members must abide by safety regulations.
各班组人员务必遵守安全条例
Wear protective equipment when leaving the cabin
出舱穿戴防护装备
to withstand high and low temperature.
以抵御高低温
Strong Radiation and Micrometeorite Impact.
强辐射与微陨石冲击
Long term extravehicular operations.
长时间舱外作业
Need to enable visual enhancement mode.
需开启视觉增强模式
Notification.
通知
According to data from the Space Situational Awareness System.
根据太空态势感知系统数据
Affected by coupling perturbation.
受耦合摄动影响
To maintain the balance of ladder weights.
为维持天梯配重平衡
Nanowire Turbine Room.
纳米丝轮机室
The length of nanowires will be regulated in the near future.
将于近期调控纳米丝长度
Raise the track height of Huanghe Station.
抬升黄河站轨道高度
To learn more consult an engineer.
请二级工程师
Go to the center axis control center.
立即前往中轴控制中枢
Confirmation of the main and auxiliary nuclear power plants of the Yellow River Station.
确认黄河站主副核电站
Both in stable operation.
均维持低功率运行
Please be at the nanofilament node.
请正在纳米丝节点
Overseas personnel servicing internal fiber optics.
检修内部光纤的舱外人员
Complete the operation and return to the cabin within 30 minutes.
于30分钟内完成作业并返舱
The special train has arrived at the high-altitude first-ring central axis orbital station.
特殊专列已抵达高空一环中轴轨道站
The flexible robotic arm engaged in transferring and docking.
柔性机械臂转运停靠中
Ask the relevant personnel to do a good job of receiving.
请相关负责人员做好接引工作
Is it here?
就是这里吗
To the right.
对
It should be here.
应该是这边
Hello Mr. Luo Ji
罗辑先生您好
I'm the person in charge of the first ring of the high-altitude station.
我是高空站一环的负责人
Welcome.
欢迎
The layout of the ladder is quite special.
天梯的布局比较特殊
I'll show you the way.
我来给您二位带路
Thanks.
谢谢
Axis work team.
中轴工作班组
Please strictly implement the rotation system.
请严格执行轮岗制度
Come this way.
来这边
Avoid prolonged exposure to weightlessness.
避免长期处于失重环境
Beware of Muscle Atrophy.
谨防肌肉萎缩
Occurrence of symptoms such as bone calcium metabolism disorder.
骨钙质代谢紊乱等症状发生
Where are we going?
我们这是去哪儿啊
We should be there soon.
应该快到了
I think you'll like it.
我想你会喜欢的
How do you know what I like?
你怎么知道我喜欢
From 6 to 8 p.m. today
本日晚6到8点
Fixed dining spots in Gaoyihuan.
高一环固定用餐点
I just know.
反正我就是知道
Boxes of space food will be distributed.
将发放太空食品盲盒
Please get it at your leisure.
请大家按需领取
This is the entrance to the Gravity Transition Channel.
这是重力过渡通道的入口
This..
他们
is this shipping something?
这是在运东西吗
It's really different than on the ground.
真的和地面完全不一样
Come.
来
Three-dimensional traffic hall.
立体交通大厅
It is the logistics hub of the whole high-altitude station.
是整个高空站的物流枢纽
All supplies from the ground
所有来自地面的补给
have to go through here.
都要经过这里
Cross-shipment to various gravity ports.
转运到各个重力港
No. 1 Gravity Port of High-altitude First Ring Road.
高空一环1号重力港
Adjusted dynamic inventory plan.
已调整动态库存方案
Ask the corresponding warehouse management personnel to coordinate the freight team.
请相应库管人员协调货运组
Adjust medical supplies inventory.
调整医疗耗材库存
Bootstrap is starting.
导引平台正在启动
Please hold on to the handrail.
请握紧扶手
Going to Gravity Port No. 2, Tianti First Ring Road.
即将前往天梯一环2号重力港
Current gravity.
当前重力
0.13G
0.13G
0.30G
0.30G
Current gravity.
当前重力
0.40G
0.40G
0.50G
0.50G
Current gravity.
当前重力
0.60G
0.60G
0.70G
0.70G
Oh right.
对了
When will Uncle Shi come to see us?
史叔叔他什么时候来找我们啊
Hes..
他呀
busy with other things.
在忙其他事
But your safety is his top priority.
可你的安全是最重要的
It's safe here.
这里挺安全的
Can we can let go now?
是不是可以松手了
We still need to be careful.
还是小心些
We are almost there.
马上就到了
The guidance platform has arrived at the No. 2 Gravity Port on the first ring of the Ladder.
导引平台已抵达天梯一环2号重力港
Mr. Luo Ji.
罗辑先生
This way please.
这边请
Walk slowly.
慢点走
There is no hurry.
不急
High altitude ring.
高空一环
The stocktaking work from F to A ring road reservoir area has been completed.
F至A环道库区盘点工作已完成
Cross-shipment work can be carried out normally in this ring road section.
该环道区间内转运工作可正常开展
Fragile high-precision goods.
易碎高精货物
Please transfer via the three-dimensional traffic hall.
请经由立体交通大厅进行转运
Avoid damage caused by vibration.
避免震动造成损耗
New superconducting material developed by microgravity lab.
由微重力实验室研发的新型超导材料
Now in production on the ground.
现已在地面正式生产
Thanks to all the staff for their hard work.
感谢各位工作人员的辛苦付出
Every small step you take
你们前进的每一步
is a leap
都是迈向胜利的
for all mankind.
一大步
Mr. Luo Ji.
罗辑先生
This way please.
这边请
We're testing the gravity well gate tomorrow.
明天要测试重力井内闸门
Hurry up.
抓紧完活
Recheck the fire protection in the flammable storage area.
易燃物库区的消防再检查一遍
Don't miss out.
别出细漏
In front is the viewing platform.
前面就是观景平台了
What's wrong?
怎么了
I wanted to ask you.
我想请您
I may never have another chance like this.
我可能再没有这样的机会了
So I would like to ask you to give a few words.
所以想请您题个字
As a souvenir.
作为纪念
What should I write?
写什么呢
Say something to the workers.
给工友们说句话
Anything.
什么都行
What do you want to say?
您最想说的
It's no problem.
没问题
We will work hard.
我们会努力的
Thank you.
谢谢您
Call me whenever you need.
有需求随时叫我
Goodbye.
再见
Mr. Luo Ji
罗辑先生
I should have brought a paintbrush.
我应该带画笔上来的
Amazing.
真的
The core parts of the general cargo spacecraft have arrived in Hong Kong.
通用货运飞船核心配件已抵港
Cargo channel air pressure balance.
货运通道气压平衡中
The inner gate is about to open.
内闸门即将开启
The cross-shipment task has been sent to the corresponding freight team.
转运任务已下发至相应货运班组
Please transfer to the dedicated warehouse in the maintenance area as soon as possible.
请尽快转运至维修区专用仓库
The seventh batch of goods is being transferred at the low-altitude transfer station.
第7批次货物正在低空中转站转运
Cargo pod heading to high-altitude transfer station.
前往高空中转站的货运舱
What is this about direct delivery?
说好的直达呢
Please wait.
请等待
This trip has to be unloaded at an intermediate station.
这趟得中间站卸货
Didn't this get checked out?
没查清楚吗
Clearly they did not hear me.
没听清
What
什么
time delay?
延时
Can't hear, can't hear.
听不清听不清
ok ok ok.
行了行了
I will figure it out on my own.
我自个儿想办法
Watch high altitude station.
打表高空站
Parking low altitude station.
停车低空站
There's more than the black car drivers in Jibei.
比暨北的黑车司机都坑
Please go to the C2 airlock chamber for the inspection team to stand by.
请检修班组前往C2气闸舱待命
Cooperate with the crew to complete the routine inspection of the cargo spacecraft
配合机组完成货运飞船常规检查
and refuel.
并进行燃料补充
Notice.
注意
Mechanical assembly lathe robotic arm malfunctioning.
机械组装车床机械臂发生故障
Please send the repair team immediately.
请维修班组立即前往维修
Pay attention.
注意了啊
Supplies to the Experimental Base.
实验基地的补给
Dump storage location 3.
转存三号储存位
Brother.
兄弟
How long are we staying here?
咱在这个站得耽搁多久啊
why are you asking me?
你问我啊
Ask the pile.
问那堆货吧
Urgent use.
急有屁用
Wait..
等着吧
T6 is off.
T6偏了
Seven o'clock direction.
七点钟方向
Adjust twenty degrees and return to normal.
调二十度再回正
Go low.
走低轨
The destination of this flight is
该班次目的地为
2718 Space Experiment Base.
2718太空实验基地
Badge.
工牌呢
Who are you with?
哪个组的
Tianti No. 1 Observation Platform.
天梯1号观景平台
Located on the outer edge of the first ring road of Gaokong Station.
位于高空站一环环道外沿
A variety of surface plants are cultivated here.
此处培植了多种地表植物
Research on space mutation and breeding
用于空间诱变育种的研究
at the same time
同时
can help people who work in the cabin for a long time
可帮助长期在舱内工作的人员
fight claustrophobia,
对抗幽闭恐惧
depression and fatigue.
抑郁及疲劳
It's sad.
好可惜
Such a beautiful universe
这么美的太阳系
and no one will see it.
以后没人能看到了
Think about it like this.
换个思路想想
Trisolarans are living beings too.
三体人也是人啊
I don't think they are good.
我觉得它们不善良
So I can't feel the beauty.
所以感受不到美
Their strategy against humans
它们对人类的策略
is a rational choice.
是一种理性的选择
It is a responsible approach to the survival of one's own race.
是对自己种族生存的一种负责任的做法
It is not about good or evil.
与善良和邪恶无关
Will you meet the Trisolarans in the
你将来会见到三体人的
future?
是吗
Maybe.
也许吧
If..
如果
I mean..
我是说
If you really beat them
如果真的打败它们
Can you?
能不能
Not kill all of them?
不要赶尽杀绝
Give them a place
给它们一块地方
to live with us.
和我们生活在一起
Zhuang Yan.
庄颜
I sometimes feel
我有时候觉得
If there's real possibility of saving the world.
真正有可能拯救世界的
It's you.
是你
I'm not a Wallfacer.
我又不是面壁者
I'm serious.
我是认真的
If there were more people like you.
如果你这样的人多一些
It would really possible for the Three-Body Civilization to negotiate with us
三体文明真的有可能跟我们谈判
instead of immediately declaring war.
而不是直接宣战
Really?
真的吗
So..
那
can you tell me now
你现在能不能告诉我
what my job is?
我的工作到底是什么
Actually
其实
your work has already begun.
你的工作已经开始了
Really?
真的吗
But..
但
but I didn't do anything.
但我什么都没做呀
Be happy.
开心吗
Use this time
这段时间
to make yourself happy.
让自己幸福快乐
This is your job.
这就是你的工作
About to arrive at the destination
即将抵达目的地
2718 Space Experiment Base.
2718太空实验基地
Are you
现在
really a wallfacer?
你是面壁者吗
Of course.
当然啊
You just want to eat, drink and be happy every day?
我只要每天吃喝玩乐
that's it?
只是这样
It's important.
这很重要啊
Think about it.
你想想看
It is obvious that in 400 years the Three-Body Problem will arrive
明明四百年后三体人才到
but, people are already living in the apocalypse.
但人们已经活在末日里了
Is that necessary?
有必要吗
Can such bitterness and hatred fight against the three-body problem?
这么苦大仇深就能对抗三体吗
Until then.
在那之前
Live happily.
开开心心活着
Live on your own terms.
照自己想法活着
You have a responsibility for yourself.
这才是对自己负责啊
Your favorite renaissance.
你最喜欢的文艺复兴
The ones with..
那些
Human Spirit.
人文精神
It's the same
也是这样啊
Doesn't art show us
艺术不就是带领我们
To look for joy and happiness?
去寻找快乐和幸福吗
I think
我觉得
your plan
你口中的计划
and my job
还有我的工作
are nonexistent.
都根本不存在
All this time I've been convincing myself
这段时间我一直在说服自己
trying to believe
努力相信
that it's all true.
这一切是真的
To believe that you are useful.
相信自己是有用的人
But not until that moment
但直到刚才那一刻
did I realize.
我才明白
Of course, why are you useless?
当然啊你怎么会没用呢
please listen to me.
请听我说完
I'm serious.
我很认真
I want to ask you.
我想问你
Who are you?
你是
Do you really need me?
真的需要我吗
Of course I need you.
当然需要啊
Didn't I say that
我不是说过吗
you are most important.
你就是第一位的
If..
如果
if you're just an ordinary person.
你只是个普通人的话
You tell me
和我说这些
that I will be very happy.
我会很开心
But in fact
但实际上
I'm not happy now.
这段时间我并不快乐
Or
或者说
I am as happy as I can be.
多快乐我就有多自责
Thank you Mr. Luo Ji.
谢谢您罗辑先生
I will remember the starry sky tonight.
我会记得今晚的星空
The pressure balance of the channel barometric chamber is completed.
通道气压舱压力平衡完毕
Inner gate open.
内闸门开启
Freight personnel are asked to enter the channel in an orderly manner with their badges.
请货运人员凭工牌有序进入通道
Be careful in the future
以后留神啊
of losing you badge.
丢了工牌
A replacement is not cheap.
补办也不便宜
Please note.
请注意
The K34 cargo cabin to the high-altitude transfer station will depart in advance.
前往高空中转站的K34货运舱将提前出发
Please prepare for boarding accordingly.
请对应班组人员做好登舱准备
Thanks.
谢了啊
Didn't you say you can't leave?
不是说走不了吗
Forget it
别想了
that's for the spaceship.
那是运飞船的
You can only go if you have a license.
有牌儿才能去
You.
你啊
Just put it here and slide it.
就搁这儿搬吧
About to unleash ball lightning.
即将释放球状闪电
Relevant staff please do a good job in data analysis.
相关工作人员请做好数据分析工作
Ghost 1 is on track.
幽灵1号按轨道运行
Arriving soon at the target area
即将抵达靶区
The lightning state of the ball is stable.
球闪状态稳定
Correct the relative position of the ball lightning and the target.
正校正球闪与标靶的相对位置
Calibration completed.
校正完毕
Confirm that the ball lightning is in the best attack position.
确认球闪处于最佳攻击位置
Ghost 1 is calculating the cloud map of the ball lightning position after two seconds.
幽灵1号正在测算两秒后的球闪位置云图
Recycling program is automatically set.
回收程序自动设置中
Ball Lightning Unleashed.
球状闪电已释放
Approaching target.
正在接近标靶
Destruction complete.
撞击已完成
Ball lightning energy redundancy is higher than expected.
球闪能量冗余高于预期值
This kind of experiment has to be in space.
这种实验还得来太空才行啊
Good.
好
When will the electromagnetic launch rail be built?
电磁发射导轨什么时候能建好
You mean the massive ball lightning experiment?
你是说大规模的球闪实验
Ask the PDC for more budget.
多问PDC要点预算不就成了
Good.
好
Mr. Tyler.
泰勒先生
I
我
am your wall breaker.
是您的破壁人